* Shop
    
    Offset
    
    * [Subscribe & Save
        
        Save up to 30%](https://www.blueland.com/collections/subscriptions)
    
    Offset

* 0

Toggle navigation menu

0

* [Subscribe & Save
    
    Up to 30% off](https://www.blueland.com/collections/subscriptions)

Secondary navigation menu

Privacy Policy
==============

Privacy Policy
--------------

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy describes how we may process your personally identifiable information or personal data (“Personal Information”), including when you visit or make a purchase from blueland.com (the “Site”).

For information on the rights of consumers under various state privacy laws, and our handling of Personal Information of residents of those states, please see the section titled “Privacy Rights for Residents of California and Certain Other States” below. Please also see below for information on the rights of consumers in various foreign countries, including the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand.

### PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

The Personal Information that we collect depends on the nature of the relationship we have with you. Below are some of the ways we may collect and use Personal Information and our legal or business purposes for doing so.

**Our Customers**

When you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain information from you to process your order, including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card numbers), email address, and phone number. We refer to this information as “Order Information.”

**  
Visitors to Our Site**

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.” Please see the section below titled “Cookies and Global Privacy Controls” for more information.

**  
Our Employees**

We collect standard employment-related information from our workforce and job applicants, including titles, names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, professional affiliations, employment and education information, usernames and passwords, government identification, banking and financial information, citizenship, health data, precise geolocation through devices used for work, military or veteran status, and on rare occasions the contents of mail, email or texts. We may also collect information related to our employees’ race or ethnicity, sexuality, health, and military or veteran status for the purposes of complying with our legal Diversity, Equity and Inclusion (DE&I) and other government reporting obligations. We refer to this information as “Employee Information.”

**  
Surveys, Promotions, and Marketing**

We send marketing emails to our customers and website visitors, often to inform you about upcoming sales, new products, or products you viewed on our Site. Sometimes these emails contain surveys that ask for demographic information, including your age, geographic location, gender, ethnicity, and education level. You may also sign up for our mailing lists by providing your email address. We refer to this information as “Marketing Information.”

###   
COOKIES AND GLOBAL PRIVACY CONTROLS

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

* “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org.
* “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.
* “Web beacons”, “tags”, and “pixels” are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

If you do not wish to be tracked via cookies, please decline cookie tracking when you visit the website, or visit the help pages of your web browser to clear your cookies. For more information on how to manage cookies, you may choose to visit unaffiliated third-party websites, such as https://allaboutcookies.org/how-to-manage-cookies. We are not responsible for, and cannot guarantee the accuracy of, the content provided on https://allaboutcookies.org.

You may also choose to install Global Privacy Controls (GPCs) on your browser. GPCs are browser signals that indicate a user’s intent to opt-out of some uses of their Personal Information on websites they visit. If our site recognizes that your browser is expressing a GPC, we will treat it as a request to opt-out of the sharing of your Personal Information and limit the use of your sensitive Personal Information collected by our site.

In some cases, we may not be able to link the GPC of your browser to other Personal Information that we have collected from you by other means. To express your intent to opt-out of our processing of Personal Information that we may have collected from you outside of our Site, please see the sections titled “Privacy Rights for Residents of California and Certain Other States” and “Privacy Rights for Residents of the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand” below.

**Do Not Track**

Although we will respond to GPCs, please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

**  
Links to Other Websites**

Our Site may also contain links to third-party web sites. These links are provided solely as a convenience to you and not as an endorsement by us of those web sites. We are not responsible for the content of linked third-party sites and make no representations regarding the privacy practices, content, or accuracy of materials on third-party web sites.  

### HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use Order Information generally to fulfill any orders placed through the Site (including processing your payment information, arranging for shipping, and providing you with invoices and/or order confirmations). Additionally, we use this Order Information to: communicate with you and provide customer service; screen our orders for potential risk or fraud; and provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services, in accordance with the preferences you have shared with us.

We use Device Information to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns). We also use Device Information to provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services, in accordance with the preferences you have shared with us.

We use Employee Information for standard employment purposes such as processing payroll, providing human resources, administering our business (including managing our employees and providing our services) and to fulfill our legal and reporting obligations.

We use Marketing Information to provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services, in accordance with the preferences you have shared with us.

### SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use it for the purposes described above. For example, we use Shopify to power our online store and share Device Information and Order Information with Shopify. You can read more about how Shopify uses your Personal Information here: https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy. We also share your Personal Information, including Device Information, Marketing Information, and Order Information, with Google Analytics and similar third parties (including Meta and Disco) to help us understand how our customers use the Site or for advertising purposes. You can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout or by disabling advertising cookies on our website.

We also share your Personal Information with our third-party service providers, in order to perform business functions such as fulfilling or shipping your orders, customer service, hosting services, communications, software and website development services, payment processing services, accounting and audit services, compliance services, quality control services, and analytics services. Our third-party service providers are only allowed to use, disclose, or retain your Personal Information for the purpose of providing these services to us, and are prohibited from selling your Personal Information. We also share Employee Information with third party service providers to provide services to our employees, such as payroll.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to prevent fraud, to respond to a subpoena other lawful request for information, or to otherwise protect our rights or the rights of others. In the event that we choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets with another business or a third-party, your personal information may also be disclosed or transferred as part of that merger or transaction.

### BEHAVIORAL ADVERTISING

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. This use includes sharing your Personal Information with third-party advertisers, including those listed below. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

You can opt out of targeted advertising by using the links below:

* Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads
* Google: https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous
* Bing: https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads

We partner with Rakuten Marketing, a third-party advertiser who may collect personal information when you interact with our site. The collection and use of this information is subject to the privacy policy located here: https://rakutenmarketing.com/legal-notices/services-privacy-policy/. You can also opt-out of Rakuten Marketing here: https://rakutenmarketing.com/legal-notices/subject-requests/

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out portal at: http://optout.aboutads.info/.

### HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We maintain generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information that we collect from unauthorized access or disclosure. We use administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect Personal Information, including for example: multi-factor authentication; physical access restrictions; electronic access restrictions and strong authentication protocols; access restriction policies; firewalls and anti-malware; and employee cybersecurity training. We also comply with payment card industry data security standards that require merchants to implement security measures for credit card information. We never have access to your credit card information, as it is tokenized following PCI-compliant standards.

While we strive to protect your Personal Information and privacy, no data transmission or storage is 100% safe. We cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information disclosed or transmitted to us and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction or inadvertent disclosure of Personal Information.

### RETAINING AND DELETING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We do not retain Personal Information for longer than reasonably necessary to fulfill the business purposes for which it was collected, conduct audits, enforce our legal rights, prevent fraud and ensure security, or comply with our legal obligations. Our retention periods for Personal Information vary depending on the nature of our relationship with you, the sensitivity of the Personal Information, and the risks involved with any related processing. We regularly review our data retention periods and update these policies as needed.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Our Site and our products are not intended for purchase or use by children. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under 18 years of age. If you are under 18, please do not submit any Personal Information on our Site.

### PRIVACY RIGHTS FOR RESIDENTS OF CALIFORNIA AND CERTAIN OTHER STATES

If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Virginia, Utah or Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, Utah or Virginia, you have certain rights regarding the use of your Personal Information. This section of the Privacy Policy describes those rights and how you can exercise them. We reserve the right to deny any requests made pursuant to the rights listed below if the law does not allow or require us to comply with them.

(1) The right to notice that Personal Information will be collected:

You have the right to request certain information about our collection and use of Personal Information over the past 12 months. The categories of information that we have collected in the past 12 months are listed below along with the general sources of that information, the purposes for which we collect it, the types of third parties to whom we have disclosed it and our criteria for how long to retain it. We update this information at least once every 12 months.

For all of the categories listed in this section: (i) we do not use this Personal Information to create profiles on individuals that produce legal or similarly significant effects; and (ii) we retain this Personal Information only for the time period necessary to achieve the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, taking into account the business needs related to providing our products (such as resolving disputes, conducting audits, and enforcing legal rights), the sensitivity of the Personal Information and risks involved, and retention requirements under applicable law. We will delete this information upon request from you, unless one of the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or the law prevents us from doing so.

_**Identifiers**_ (such as a name, postal or email address, IP address, account name, Social Security number, driver’s license number, or passport number):

* Purposes of processing: We collect this type of information for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: managing orders; employment services (e.g., payroll, insurance, employment eligibility); marketing and advertising; and complying with our legal obligations (e.g., reporting to government agencies). The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you or from third party advertising partners (such as Google Analytics).
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we have disclosed information in this category to: our service providers (e.g., shipping, IT support, customer relations); marketing outlets (including cookies and IP address information to Google Ads and Meta, for which we may receive analytics, advertising, and other benefits in return); and government agencies (e.g., EEOC).
* Selling and Advertising: We do not sell any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, we may share it for the purpose of cross-context behavioral or targeted advertising with our advertising partners (e.g., Google Ads, Meta, TikTok, Amazon) in order to deliver advertisements to you.

_**Personal Information categories listed in Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)**_ (such as your name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license, employment history, financial information, medical information or health insurance information):

* Purposes of processing: We collect this type of information for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: managing orders; employment services (e.g., payroll, insurance, employment eligibility); marketing and advertising; and complying with our legal obligations (e.g., reporting to government agencies). The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you. We may also collect your name and contact information from third party advertising partners (such as Google Analytics).
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we have disclosed information in this category to: our service providers (e.g., shipping, IT support, customer relations, payroll and insurance); marketing outlets (including cookies and IP address information to Google Ads and Meta, for which we may receive analytics, advertising, and other benefits in return); and government agencies (e.g., EEOC).
* Selling and Advertising: We do not sell any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, we may share names and contact information for the purpose of cross-context behavioral or targeted advertising with our advertising partners (e.g., Google Ads, Meta, TikTok, Amazon) in order to deliver advertisements to you.

_**Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law**_ (such as age, race, ancestry, citizenship, religion, marital status, medical condition, gender identity or expression, pregnancy or childbirth, sexual orientation, veteran or military status, or genetic information):

* Purposes of processing: We collect this type of information for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: employment services (e.g., payroll, insurance, employment eligibility); marketing and advertising; and complying with our legal obligations (e.g., reporting to government agencies). The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you.
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we may have disclosed information in this category to: our service providers (payroll and insurance); marketing outlets (e.g., Google Ads); and government agencies (e.g., EEOC).
* Selling and Advertising: We do not sell any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, we may share information revealing your age for the purpose of cross-context behavioral or targeted advertising with our advertising partners (e.g., Google Ads, Meta, TikTok, Amazon) in order to deliver advertisements to you.

**Internet or other similar network activit**y (such as browsing history or a consumer’s interaction with a website, application or advertisement):

* Purposes of processing: Like most websites, ours automatically collects information from your browser or device when you visit our site. We collect this type of information for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: improving our site (e.g., tracking page visits); for IT support and maintenance; preserving our rights and legal defenses (e.g., investigating fraud); and securing our site (e.g., preventing hacking or misuse). The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
* Sources: We may collect this information directly from you through your internet use.
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we may have disclosed information in this category to: service providers (e.g., IT support, web hosting) and marketing partners (including cookies and IP address information to Google Ads and Meta, for which we may receive analytics, advertising, and other benefits in return).
* Selling and Advertising: We do not sell any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, we may share information in this category the purpose of cross-context behavioral or targeted advertising with our advertising partners (e.g., Google Ads, Meta, TikTok, Amazon) in order to deliver advertisements to you.

_**Geolocation data**_ (such as a person’s physical location or movements):

* Purposes of processing: Like most websites, ours automatically collects your IP address from your browser or device, which can be associated with a physical address. However, we do not use this information to geolocate you. We collect this type of information for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: improving our site (e.g., tracking page visits); for IT support; preserving our rights and legal defenses (e.g., investigating fraud); and securing our site (e.g., preventing hacking or misuse). On rare occasions we issue laptops or other devices to our employees. We can track the location of these devices for security and device management purposes. The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.We Use Your Personal Information” for more information.
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you through your internet or device use.
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we may have disclosed information in this category to: service providers (e.g., IT support). Although we do not use IP addresses for geolocation purposes, our site shares cookies and IP address information with Google Ads, for which we may receive analytics and other benefits in return.

**Commercial information** (such as records of personal property, products or services purchased or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies):

* We collect this type of information for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: managing orders; customizing our Site; and marketing and advertising. The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you or from third party advertising partners (such as Google Analytics).
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we have disclosed information in this category to: our service providers (e.g., shipping, IT support, customer relations) and marketing outlets (including cookies and IP address information to Google Ads and Meta, for which we may receive analytics, advertising, and other benefits in return).
* Selling and Advertising: We do not sell any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, we may share it for the purpose of cross-context behavioral or targeted advertising with our advertising partners (e.g., Google Ads, Meta, TikTok, Amazon) in order to deliver advertisements to you.

_**Professional or employment-related information**_ (such as job history or performance evaluations) and _**Nonpublic education information**_ (such as grades, transcripts, student financial information or disciplinary records):

* Purposes of processing: We collect this type of information from our employees and applicants for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: managing our employees (e.g., hiring, performance evaluations).
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you or from your former employers or other third-party employment services.
* Sharing: We do not share this information unless requested by you.
* Selling or advertising: We do not sell information in this category or share it for advertising purposes.

_**Inferences drawn from other Personal Information**_ (such as a profile reflecting a person’s preferences, characteristics, trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities or aptitudes):

* We collect this type of information, including your Order Information, for a variety of business purposes, including but not limited to: managing orders; customizing our Site; and marketing and advertising. The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
* Sources: We collect this information directly from you or from third party advertising partners (such as Google Analytics).
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we have disclosed information in this category to: our service providers (e.g., shipping, IT support, customer relations) and marketing outlets (including cookies and IP address information to Google Ads and Meta, for which we may receive analytics, advertising, and other benefits in return).
* Selling and Advertising: We do not sell any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, we may share it for the purpose of cross-context behavioral or targeted advertising with our advertising partners (e.g., Google Ads, Meta, TikTok, Amazon) in order to deliver advertisements to you.

We do not collect or process Personal Information in the following categories: _**sensory data**_ (such as any audio, electronic, visual, olfactory or similar information); or _**biometric information**_ (such as fingerprints, faceprints, voiceprints, or other physical patterns).

**Sensitive Personal Information**

The categories of Sensitive Personal Information we may collect from you, and that we have collected from consumers in the past 12 months, are listed below along with the purposes for which we collect this information. For all of the categories listed in this section: (i) we do not sell your Sensitive Personal Information or use it for targeted or cross-context behavioral advertising; (ii) we do not create profiles on individuals that produce legal or similarly significant effects or use Sensitive Personal Information to infer characteristics about an individual; and (iii) we keep your Sensitive Personal Information for the time period necessary to achieve the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement, taking into account the business needs related to providing our products and services (such as resolving disputes, conducting audits, and enforcing legal rights), the sensitivity of the Personal Information and risks involved, and retention requirements under applicable law. We will delete this information upon request from you, unless one of the purposes described in this Privacy Statement or the law prevents us from doing so.

**Social Security, driver’s license, state identification card, or passport number; racial or ethnic origin; sex life or sexual orientation; status as transgender or nonbinary; or health or medical information:**

* Purposes of processing: We generally to not process these types of sensitive Personal Information unless they relate directly to our obligations as an employer, including providing human resources services or complying with our DE&I reporting obligations.
* Sources: We may collect this information directly from you.
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we may have disclosed information in this category to: service providers (e.g., insurance processors) and to government agencies (e.g., EEOC).

_**Racial or ethnic origin, sex life, sexual orientation, or health or medical information:**_

* Purposes of processing: We generally to not process these types of sensitive Personal Information unless they relate directly to our obligations as an employer, including providing human resources services or complying with our DE&I reporting obligations. The purposes for which we collect this information may vary based on our relationship with you. Please see the section above titled “How We Use Your Personal Information” for more information.
* Sources: We may collect this information directly from you.
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we may have disclosed information in this category to: service providers (e.g., insurance processors) and to government agencies (e.g., EEOC).

_**The contents of your mail, email and text messages where we are not the intended recipient:**_

* Purposes of processing: On rare occasions we issue laptops or other devices to our employees. Although it is not our practice to monitor the communications made through these devices, we reserve the right to review such communications for legitimate business purposes, including but not limited to: providing our products and services; managing our employees, contractors and applicants (e.g., evaluating performance or investigating misuse); and securing our devices (e.g., preventing hacking or fraud).
* Sources: We may collect this information directly from you through your use of our devices.
* Sharing: In the past 12 months, we may have disclosed information in this category to: service providers (e.g., IT support).

We do not collect any sensitive Personal Information revealing your _**religious or philosophical beliefs; genetic data; union membership; precise geolocation; status as a victim of a crime;**_ your _**biometric information for identification purposes;**_ your _**account login combined with a password;**_ or your _**financial account, debit card or credit card number combined with any required security or access code, password, or credentials allowing access to an account.**_ We also do not collect Personal Information of _**children.**_

(2) The right to know what Personal Information has been collected, sold or disclosed for a business purpose, and to whom it was sold or disclosed:

You have the right to know what Personal Information we have collected about you in the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable request, we may disclose to you:

* The categories of Personal Information we’ve collected about you
* The categories of sources for the Personal Information we’ve collected about you
* Our business or commercial purpose for collecting and/or selling that Personal Information
* The categories of Personal Information that we’ve shared with third parties
* The categories of third parties with whom we’ve shared that Personal Information (Oregon residents have the right to request a list of third parties with whom we’ve shared Personal Information)
* The specific pieces of Personal Information we’ve collected about you

Pursuant to state privacy laws, we may deny your request, in whole or in part, including to comply with federal, state or local laws or to prevent disclosure of information that we are otherwise legally prohibited from disclosing. In the event that we deny your request, we will inform you of the basis for such denial.

(3) The right to opt-out of the sale or sharing of Personal Information or limit the use of Sensitive Personal Information:

You have the right to direct companies not to sell your Personal Information. You also have the right to direct companies not to share your Personal Information for the purpose of (i) targeted advertising or (ii) for profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects. Additionally, you have the right to request that we refrain from processing, or limit the use of your Sensitive Personal Information.

If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Virginia, Utah or Connecticut and would like to make an opt-out request pursuant to any of the rights described in this section, you may do so by following the instructions on the **form found here**. Alternatively, residents of California, Colorado, Virginia, Utah or Connecticut may make the same requests by contacting us at the information listed above or by emailing us at hello@blueland.com, Attn: Privacy Officer.

(4) The right to have your Personal Information deleted:

You have the right to request that we delete any of your Personal Information that we have collected, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we may delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your Personal Information from our records, unless prohibited by law.

(5) The right to correct your Personal Information:

You have the right to request that we correct inaccuracies in the Personal Information that we maintain about you. In responding, we may consider the nature of the Personal Information, the purposes for processing it, and the totality of the circumstances.

(7) The right to data portability:

You have the right to request a copy of the Personal Information that we maintain about you in a commonly used, easily readable format.

(8) The right to nondiscrimination as a result of exercising these rights.

Finally, you have the right to be protected from discrimination by any business as a result of exercising your privacy rights. For example, as a result of you exercising these rights, we will never deny you goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a different level or quality of goods or services.

If you believe we have violated any of your rights listed in this Privacy Statement, please contact us at the information below.

Exercising your state privacy rights:

If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, Utah or Virginia and would like to make a request pursuant to any of the rights described in this section, you may do so by following the instructions on the **form found here**. Alternatively, you may make the same requests by calling us at (833) 399-0397, or by emailing us at hello@blueland.com, Attn: Privacy Officer.

In order to protect your Personal Information, we are required to verify that any person making a request under this section is in fact you or your authorized agent. In order to verify the identity of the person making a request, we may ask you to provide the following information: your email address and prior order or payment information. We will use this information only for the purposes of verifying that your request is authentic.

Once we receive your request, we will respond within 10 business days and inform you if we need any more information in order to verify your request. We will provide the information you requested within 45 days of your request. If we require more than 45 days to respond to your request, we will inform you of the reasons why. For requests from California consumers to opt out of the sale or sharing of their Personal Information for the purposes of cross-context behavioral advertising, or requests to limit the use of sensitive Personal Information, we will respond within 15 days.

We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable consumer request unless it is excessive, repetitive or manifestly unfounded.

Exercising privacy rights as the resident’s authorized agent:

If you are a consumer and you would like to authorize an agent to submit requests on your behalf, in order to exercise your rights under the state privacy laws listed herein, please designate your authorized agent by filling out the **form found here**. Alternatively, you may authorize an agent by contacting us at the addresses and phone number listed above.

In order to verify your identity when you are authorizing an agent to act on your behalf, we may ask you to provide the following information: your email address and prior order or payment information. We may require written and signed authorization from you before an agent may act on your behalf. We will use this information only for the purposes of verifying that your request is authentic.

Your right to appeal our response to your privacy rights requests:

Residents of Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, and Virginia have the right to appeal our decisions in response to the exercise of your privacy rights requests. To initiate an internal appeal, please contact us at the addresses or phone number listed above or by filling out the **form found here**. We will respond to your request for an internal appeal within 45 days, but we may take up to 60 additional days for good cause. If you are unhappy with the results of your appeal, you may contact your state attorney general.

### PRIVACY RIGHTS FOR RESIDENTS OF THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA, THE UNITED KINGDOM, CANADA, AUSTRALIA, AND NEW ZEALAND

The ways in which we process your personal information may vary based on our relationship with you. Please see the sections above titled “How We Use Your Personal Information” and “Privacy Rights for Residents of California and Certain Other States” for a description of the ways that we process your personal information and how long we retain it, based on the types of interactions you have with us.

The legal bases for which we may process personal information of residents of the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand are listed below:

* The performance of any contractual relationship we have with you
* Where it is necessary for compliance with our legal obligations
* Where you have provided your consent to certain types of processing
* Where it is in our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of our partners, affiliates, clients, and service providers (provided these are not overridden by your interests and fundamental rights and freedoms), such as:
    * To provide our products and services
    * To respond to your requests and inquiries
    * To administer our business, including marketing and analysis
    * To prevent and detect fraud or security threats
    * To comply with applicable laws, regulations or ethical obligations

We use administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect personal information from unauthorized access or disclosure. However, while we strive to protect your personal information and privacy, no data transmission or storage is 100% safe. We do not retain personal information for longer than reasonably necessary to fulfill the business purpose(s) for which it was collected, with some exceptions (e.g., for security purposes or complying with our legal obligations).

**  
Transferring Data Abroad**

Your personal information may be stored and processed in any country where we have offices or servers or in which we engage service providers, including in the United States, which may have different data protection and data processing laws than those in your country. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing, and processing. Our internal policies require all of our offices to comply with this Privacy Policy and ensure a level of protection for personal information at least as protective as that mandated by the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand. Any such transfer shall take place only in accordance with and as permitted by the law of your jurisdiction. In all cases, we shall apply the provisions of this Privacy Policy to your personal information wherever it is located.

**  
Your Rights**

Residents of the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand have the right to receive or reasonably access the personal information that we process, request a portable copy of that information, and the ability to review, correct, delete, restrict, or object to the processing of such information. You may also have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal information at any time by using the contact information at the bottom of this section.

All of these rights are subject to certain conditions and exemptions. Although we make good faith efforts to provide individuals with access to their personal information, there may be circumstances in which we are unable to provide access, including but not limited to when it would compromise others’ privacy or other legitimate rights, when the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual’s privacy, or when the information is commercially proprietary. If we determine that access should be restricted in any particular instance, we will endeavor to provide you with an explanation of why that determination has been made and a contact point for any further inquiries. To protect your privacy, we will take commercially reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to or making any changes to your personal information.

If you would like to exercise your privacy rights, please let us know by contacting us at the information below.  

Residents of the European Economic Area and the United Kingdom may report privacy complaints directly to their local data protection authorities. See https://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index\_en.htm for more information. You may also contact us to be directed to the relevant authorities for your jurisdiction.  

**CHANGES**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. Please check back regularly to ensure you have up-to-date notice.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on April 15, 2024.  

**CONTACT US**

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by e-mail at hello@blueland.com or by mail using the details provided below:

One Home Brands Inc.  
104 W 27th St, Fl 7  
New York NY 10001, United States

Our emails are zero waste, too
------------------------------

Subscribe to get exclusive deals, zero waste tips, and product launches—no spam, no waste.

Email AddressSubmit

You've joined the movement!

Oops, something went wrong

* ### Shop
    
* ### About
    
* ### Help
    
* ### Good Stuff
    
    * 
    * 

Shop

About

Help

* 
* 

Copyright 2024 Blueland

* Copyright 2024 Blueland

* 

* 

Your Cart

0

Your cart is empty

Explore Our Bestsellers
-----------------------

[

Bestseller

35% Kit Savings](https://www.blueland.com/products/the-clean-suite)

[Clean Suite Kit](https://www.blueland.com/products/the-clean-suite)$98

---------------------------------------------------------------------------

No Reviews Yet

Quick Add

[

Bestseller](https://www.blueland.com/products/hand-soap-refill-packs)

[Hand Soap Refill Packs](https://www.blueland.com/products/hand-soap-refill-packs)$12.50

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

No Reviews Yet

Quick Add

[

Bestseller](https://www.blueland.com/products/dishwasher-starter-set)

[Dishwasher Starter Set](https://www.blueland.com/products/dishwasher-starter-set)$25

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

No Reviews Yet

Quick Add

[

](https://www.blueland.com/products/laundry-starter-set)

[Laundry Starter Set](https://www.blueland.com/products/laundry-starter-set)$25

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

No Reviews Yet

Quick Add

[

Bestseller](https://www.blueland.com/products/toilet-cleaner-starter-set)

[Toilet Bowl Cleaner Starter Set](https://www.blueland.com/products/toilet-cleaner-starter-set)$23

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

No Reviews Yet

Quick Add
